DOMINIKKUNDEL

Web Developer | Software Engineer | P Dublin, Ireland

education

Jacobs University **Bremen**

Bremen Germany

2011-09 to 2014-06

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Graduated with a GPA of 1.85 (German Scale)

Bachelor thesis topic: Performance Improvement, Mobile Development and Feature Implementation for PlanetServer. Grade: 1.0

work experience

Microsoft Corporation 2014-11 to date

Software Engineer

Dublin Ireland

Member of the Marketplace team in the Office Extensibility division. Developing features for the Office Store and the respective in-client experiences.

- > Owner of Usability and UI. Providing training and guidelines for UI development
- > Member of the Office Open Source experts providing assistance inside the Office organization for consuming/contributing to OSS.

jacobsHack! 2014-02 to date

Co-founder and Advisor, former Main-Organizer Bremen, Germany

Founded jacobsHack! as an initially internal hackathon at Jacobs University Bremen to motivate fellow students to work on cool projects outside of the academic schedule. Main-organized the first externally open jacobsHack! edition in October 2014 as one of the first student hackathons in Europe. Currently active as an advisor for what is at the moment the most international student hackathon in Europe.

Highlights:

- > Secured more than 20,000€ from sponsors such as Microsoft, Google
- In Fall 2015 180 students from 20 countries and 40 nationalities participated.

CodeCombat

2014-05 to 2014-08

Google Summer of Code Student

San Francisco, CA, USA

Improved the coding experience in the CodeCombat editor by by extending the Ace-based editor with various new features such as an improved autocomplete.

Jacobs University Bremen 2013-09 to 2014-06

Teaching Assistant

Bremen Germany

Providing support for the students by holding tutorials, reviewing and grading code assignments and providing on-site assistance during lectures.

Highlights:

- > Programming in Java Courses
- Software Engineering Lab

Microsoft Corporation 2013-06 to 2013-08

Software Development Engineer in Test Intern Redmond, WA, USA

Developed a Local, Component-level Monitoring prototype using an existing, proven monitoring technology within Office365. Provided feedback to the owning engineering on SDK changes required for broader adoption.

SAP SE

2012-07 to 2012-08

Developer Intern Potsdam, Germany

Built user interfaces based on the SAP in-memory database system HANA using two different HTML5 and JavaScript based SAP toolkits.

Highlights:

- Created guidelines for developing applications with SAP UI 5
- > Used expertise in web development to consult the team in the process of developing a new prototype.

dominik.kundel@gmail.com

@dkundel

f fb.com/dominik402

in de.linkedin.com/in/dkundel

about me

I'm a sociable geek with a passion for hackathons, web development, design and teaching.

skills

Programming / Scripting Languages

- > JavaScript/TypeScript
- > HTML
- > CSS/LESS/SASS
- C++
- C#
- Java
- Ruby

Frameworks

- > Node.JS / Express
- > Angular.JS
- > Backbone.JS
- Ionic / Cordova

awards

Honorary Membership

2011-06-05

by Deutsche Mathematiker Vereinigung

Received an honorary membership in the Deutsche Mathematiker Vereinigung (German Mathematician Association) for excellent results in the final high school exams.

Honorary Membership

2011-06-05

by Deutsche Physikalische Gesellschaft

Received an honorary membership in the Deutsche Physikalische Gesellschaft (German Physics Association) for excellent results in the final high school exams.

Best Overall App

2011-09-11

by Facebook World Hack Judges

Awarded 'Best Overall App' by the judges of Facebook World Hack Berlin for the app 'Social Roadtrip'.

languages

German: mother tongue English: bilingual proficiency

profiles

Website

f fb.com/dominik402

in de.linkedin.com/in/dkundel

aithub/dkundel

♦ codepen/dkundel

volunteering

CoderDojo

2015-02 to date

Teacher and Dojo-Expert for HTML/CSS/JS

Dublin, Ireland

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people. Assisting in the local Microsoft Dublin chapter of CoderDojo, running bi-weekly classes to teach young people HTML/CSS/JS and give support for other programming questions.

The Garage

2015-06 to date

Committee Member Dublin, Ireland

Part of the committee running the Dublin chapter of The Garage. Providing the employees at Microsoft Ireland an environment where they can be creative and work on side projects. Additionally helping to organize bi-weekly SLAC (Skip Lunch And Code) sessions where members can gather, present technology, and ask for input or support. Occasionally giving talks about modern web development or other fascinating technologies.

Computer Science Club

2011-09 to 2014-06

Member and President

Bremen, Germany

Initially a member and from 2013 to 2014 president of the CS Club at Jacobs University. Organized the yearly Linux Install Fest for freshmen, weekly meetings with various (technical) presentations, preparation sessions for tech interviews and mock interviews with members of the CS Club. Founded jacobsHack! during the duration of the presidency.

Viva Con Agua e.V.

2011-06 to 2014-11

Supporter and member of the local chapter Bremen, Germany

Viva Con Agua is a non-profit organization that is trying to solve fresh water problems in countries with the lack of easy access to freshwater installments and sanitary areas. In order to achieve that Viva Con Agua collaborates with artists and musicians to find creative ways of raising money. Raised money at concerts and events of supporting artists and worked on new creative ways to raise money.